#### Contact

LinkedIn.com/in/kayawinn kayawinn@outlook.com 503.756.1837

# Kaya Winn

Engineering Manager, Infrastructure and SRE

Portland, Oregon area

Leader with extensive proven experience spanning the whole lifecycle from team building, architecting, to building and supporting scalable and highly available infrastructures and operations. Experience developing business critical applications or integration services for large hosted application providers or for enterprise applications.

### Experience

InVision
Senior Engineering Manager
January 2018 - Present

Managed globally distributed platform engineering teams delivering highly scalable cloud applications. Established a culture of trust, transparency and sharing to drive cohesion and performance. Heavy reliance on Kubernetes, AWS, Terraform, Golang

- Manage two development teams and one ops team focused on delivering tooling for DevOps and Observability systems
- Responsible for growing the team, developing individual engineers, roadmap and vision and being ultimately responsible for effective execution
- Reduced infrastructure costs \$4M+ through aggressive optimization, machine learning for Kubernetes resource management, running 50% of production on spot instances, consolidation of third party services and aggressive RI utilization
- Established culture of automation, implemented GitOps deployments and Argo Workflows to toil and increase developer velocity, refactored Terraform infrastructure provisioning for one touch deployments
- Worked across Platform and Product orgs to ensure tested and data driven operational readiness of applications
- Maintained multi-year forecasts and strengthened relationship with Finance and other senior staff on strategic business planning
- Created observability team to drive metrics collection, alerting, SLOs and visualization and work to scale development of services
- Extensively recruited across platform: engineers, managers, TPM, VP
- Managed multiple third-party vendors, including RFP's, vendor selection and contract negotiations
- Managed portfolio and product roadmaps

Welcome Home Health Engineering Manager October 2016 – January 2018

Helped grow early stage company and focused on solutions to streamline operations and reduce capital expense.

 Provided project leadership and architecture for HIPAA compliant application for patient data storage and analysis

#### International Visits:

Africa Kenya South Africa

Americas
Belize
Brazil
Canada
Guatemala
Honduras
Mexico

Asia Singapore Hong Kong

Europe France Germany Netherlands Portugal Spain UK

- Lead development of AWS Lambda based ETL application reducing infra cost 80%.
- Developed optimized data collection and qualifying procedures

Trans World Health Services

Technical Project Manager

(December 2014 - June 2016)

Managed multiple projects from greenfield to refactoring legacy applications.

- Led scrums
- Worked directly with customers, users and product team on visioning, features and release management
- Conducted HIPAA audit and managed code changes to ensure compliance
- Notable achievements from team include:
- Released ERP, e-commerce flight management system
- Released HIPAA compliant web and iOS tele-medical application

#### Nike

Senior Project Manager

September 2014 – December 2014

Working within the PMO on ServiceNow implementation to de-silo data from across the company to standup the service catalog.

- Worked closely with developers and data engineers to ensure proper integration
- Led project teams in development and execution of project plans from initiation through closeout. Coached and mentored junior project managers
- Notable achievements from team include:
- Delivered data normalization and service catalog project on time in conjunction with enterprise scale implementation.

#### HTG

Service Manager

August 2012 – September 2014

Grew the business by expanding and diversifying the product catalog to establish a strong nationwide footprint of services that resulted in substantial revenue growth and new business opportunity. Responsible managing co-lo and remote project and engineering staff.

- Managed multiple nationwide IT projects for diverse external clients
- Conducted requirements analysis/discovery and developed proposals and SOW's
- Extensive recruiting for FTE and temporary project roles
- Maintained vendor relationships and agreements
- Notable achievements from team include:
- Realized \$8M revenue increase resulting from expanded service catalog, establishing data center, and fleet services
- Amazon Locker: Designed and managed end to end deployment and maintenance program enabling nationwide debut in the United States

**Neofocal Systems** 

**Project Manager** 

September 2010 – June 2012

- Oversaw multiple projects focused on implementing scalable processes for semiconductor manufacturer applying waterfall and agile processes
- Analyzed and consolidated data, bookkeeping and reconciliation

• Implemented inventory management system to improve R&D cycle time and

American Red Cross

Director

(June 2008 - August 2010)

- Responsible for managing multiple disaster teams in six counties
- Preparation of project schedules, budgets, training, and communications
- Initiated email migration to enterprise G Suites consolidating 2400 separate email systems into one corporate system
- Disaster Service Technology supervisor responsible for staffing and network operations
- Coordinated training exercises with FEMA and county emergency teams
- Applied GIS tools to support donor and disaster operations

# **Education and Training**

University of Texas at Arlington - Management Information Systems

PMP - PMI Project Management Professional #1848259

AWS - Solutions Architect Associate (SAA)

AWS - Developer Associate (CDA)

FedRAMP - Cloud Security Provider

**Certified HIPAA Administrator (CHA)** 

## **Community and Volunteerism**

First Responder, Crisis Mental Health Counselor, Trainer Various Organizations (Black Rock City, LLC; AfrikaBurn, Boom) 2004 -2015

 Shift supervisor, training lead, peer counselor and first responder for 80,000 person event. Responsible for operations management, training development, teaching, incident coordination, law enforcement liaison

American Red Cross

May 2006 – June 2010

 Disaster Services Technology Supervisor, Disaster Committee member, local and national disaster response, including deployment for Hurricane Humberto, 2007 Midwest flooding, Hurricane Ike relief; California Wildfires 2008 radio operations and network setup

**MOPS Manual** 

2011 - 2014

 As editor and author worked for three years with a team of 45 authors, clinicians and researchers to draft best practices providing crisis mental health services in communities lacking medical or mental health infrastructure

# Chemists Without Borders 2009

 Developed scalable purification system based the chlor-alkali process to provide safe drinking water when civil water systems are not available postdisaster